# FRONT-END DEVELOPER GEORGE REGINALD NGOWI

### 16421 FERNANDO WAY W ROSEMOUNT, MN 55068 571-201-4521

georgetiti84@gmail.com

**Career Overview** 

I have 4+ years of Front-End web development experience with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript plus 1+ for UX/UI design. I am a multitasker who thrives in fast-paced environment. I have experience working in teams and individual projects. I am also an expert time manager and communicator.

#### Technical Skills

- Html5 & Css3
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- Ajax
- Angular
- Bootstrap
- Responsive Web Design
- React framework
- Express.js
- Photoshop, Sketch and Illustrator
- Adobe Spark / Flex

- UX Design
- Java
- Database architecture
- Python
- Rstudio
- Oracle Database & SQL
- Git (Github & BitBucket)
- > SDLC
- Agile Methodology
- SublimeText 3, Visual Studio, eclipse

Work Experience —

### 05/2013 to 03/2014

## Learning and work with different Front-End language as student (Html, CSS, JavaScript, SQL and jQuery)

- > Started working with my Personal project and practice with freecodeCamp for JavaScript and reading the exposed code in the different projects.
- Writing plain JavaScript fluently and efficiently.
- Learning Front-end development with Treehouse and Udemy using HTML5 and CSS3 techniques, Bootstrap frameworks backed by jQuery and other JavaScript frameworks to enable optimum user experience throughout the site
- Learning to be passion to stay ahead of the curve on front end technology and development trends in the ongoing project.

#### 03/2014 to 05/2015

# Front-End Developer(Louisiana) Independent Project

- Turn design pages and specific components into HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Developed and maintained legacy applications
- Using Responsive layout for improved usability.
- Worked with a team of developers to resolve front-end and CSS issues
- Working within an Agile environment
- Slight experienced using ECMA Script specification and modern frameworks
- > Daily testing of peers' code (QA testing) using Jira, and Visual Studio
- Utilized branching when working in shared environments with team members
- > To write and edit SQL
- To use relational database technology.
- Use Knowledge of Oracle database products

Developed a budgeting app that picks up where other leave off—ease of use.

- Backend: Google Firebase BaaS for security, Real-time NoSQL DB
- Frontend: Html, CSS, JavaScript
- ➤ Tools: Sublime Text 3. CLI
- > Framework: AngularJS 1 MVC

#### 06/2015 to 10/2017

# Us Army Military (Fort Polk) Parachute Rigger and IT Solutions

- Works with Military as Active Duty Packing Parachute for Airborne Missions.
- > Training for new soldier for Spark software.
- > Provide IT Solutions in a Rigger detachment for Spark software.
- > Do back up for Spark and schedule monthly meeting with IT team for Spark Updates.
- Unit Advisor for Enlisted new soldier for Parachute and Spark Training.
- ➤ I have ability to support multiple projects at the same time
- Created multiple reports for vendors using Telerik, and stored procedures

#### 01/2018 to 05/2018

## Independent Project (Minnesota) UX/UI Designer

- Designed dynamic and highly interactive features using JavaScript and CSS libraries.
- Maintained a web app designed by HTML5 and jQuery for mobile reporting
- > Design UI for web, mobile and desktop
- > Create Mockups, site maps, Information Architecture diagrams, Navigational models, process flows and UI component designs
- Working in designing UI screens and screen flow.
- > Experienced in working with advanced database
- Conduct user research remotely and in-person, and testing.
- > Implements Bootstrap, jQuery, AngularJS and other JavaScript and CSS frameworks.
- Utilize Photoshop and Illustrator as the part of project.

### Education & Training—

- ➤ Masters of Data Science University of St Thomas, Minnesota USA (Sept 2017 Present)
- ➤ Udemy code Front End Web Developer (Dec 2017 Feb 2018)
- Treehouse code Front End Web Developer (Jan 2014- June 2016)
- Freecodecamp- JavaScript (June 2013- March 2014)
- Graduate Certificate in Information Systems Virginia International University, Virginia, USA (May 2013)
- ➢ Bachelor of Science in Civil and Structural Engineering − Dar es Salaam University, Dar es Salaam, Tanzania (Nov 2010)

Portfolio	
- I of tions	

> UX/UI design and Front-end web develop Portfolio it is In Progressing......!